求救信号肯定来自这一扇区
Distress call definitely came from
的某个星系，舰长
one of the solar systems in this sector, captain.
能再精确一点吗？
Can you pinpoint it any closer?
不行
Negative.
信号很混乱，只收到了“星座号”几个字
It was so badly garbled, all we got was the name "Constellation."
- 然后就失去联系了 - 舰长？
- Then we lost it. - Sir?
我们现在位于L370星系
We're now within the limits of System L370
但是无法定位…
but I can't seem to locate...
舰长，传感器显示整个星系都被摧毁了
Captain, sensors show this entire solar system has been destroyed.
只剩下岩石和小行星
Nothing left but rubble and asteroids.
难以置信
That's incredible.
星系中的恒星完好无损
The star in this system is still intact.
只有新星能造成这样的结果
Only a nova could destroy like that.
然而，舰长
Nonetheless, captain
我们去年绘制的地图显示这里有七颗行星
sensors show nothing but debris
如今传感器上显示的只有碎片
where we charted seven planets last year.
继续搜索模式
Continue search pattern.
是，舰长
Aye, aye, sir.
进入L374星系范围内，舰长
Entering limits of System L374, sir.
扫描器上也显示出相同的摧毁痕迹
Scanners show the same evidence of destruction.
这扇区的所有星系都成了碎石块
Every solar system in this sector blasted to rubble,
可还是没有一点儿星座号的迹象
and still no sign of the Constellation.
马特·德克尔是星座号的指挥官，到底发生了什么？
Matt Decker's in command. What could have happened?
舰长，这一星系最中心的两颗行星似乎依然完整
Captain, the two innermost planets of this system appear to be intact.
舰长，我收到了一艘飞船的求救信号
Sir, I'm picking up a ship's disaster beacon.
尝试联系她，中尉
Try to raise her, lieutenant.
传感器有信号了，舰长
I have it on the sensors, captain.
外形像是一艘星舰
By configuration, a starship.
停在太空中，似乎处于漂流状态
Stopped in space, she appears to be drifting.
没有回应，舰长，只能收到自动信号
No answer, captain. All I get is the automatic beacon.
传感器记录不到正常的能量输出
Sensors not recording normal energy output.
接近她，苏鲁先生
Approach course, Mr. Sulu.
是星座号
It's the Constellation.
- 看呐 - 摧毁了这个类太阳系的东西
- Look at that. - She may have been wrecked
可能也毁了她
by whatever destroyed these solar systems.
她被攻击了
She was attacked.
红色警报！红色警报！进入战斗岗位
Red alert! Red alert! Man your battle stations.
红色警报，红色警报，进入战斗岗位
Red alert. Red alert. Man your battle stations.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：诺阿诺阿
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第六集
末日机器
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu.
所有相位炮就位，做好准备
All phaser banks manned and ready.
很好，启动所有传感器，扫描周边区域
Very good. Initiate full sensor scan of the immediate area
- 以确定是否存在其他飞船 - 是，舰长
- for any other vessel. - Aye, sir.
帕莫尔中尉
Lieutenant Palmer.
联系不到星座号，舰长，依然能收到求救信号
I can't raise the Constellation, sir. I'm still getting the distress beacon,
但是子空间干扰很强烈
but there's heavy subspace interference.
- 几乎要阻断信号 - 继续尝试
- It's almost blocking the signal. - Keep trying.
史波克，全面评估星座号的损伤
Mr. Spock, a full evaluation of the damage to the Constellation.
动力机组停止工作
All power plants dead.
储备电力功率非常低
Reserve energy banks operative at a very low power level.
生命维持系统呢？
Life-support systems?
同样功率很低
Also operative at a low power level.
舰桥完全损毁
The entire Bridge is damaged
且不宜生存
and uninhabitable.
星舰其他部分似乎还能维持生命
The rest of the ship seems able to sustain life.
- 辐射水平？ - 正常
- Radiation levels? - Normal.
但是子空间干扰使得读数十分困难
But subspace interference makes readings difficult.
这一区域没有其他飞船，舰长 所有扫描器显示一切正常
No other vessels in the area, captain. All scanners show clear.
全体都有，进入黄色警报，战斗岗位待命
All hands, go to yellow alert. Stand by battle stations.
中尉，传令麦考伊医生，史考特和损管队
Lieutenant, have Dr. McCoy, Mr. Scott and a damage-control party
- 来传送室向我报道 - 是，舰长
- report to me in the Transporter Room. - Aye, sir.
我们即将登陆星座号，史波克先生，你来接任指挥
We're going to board her. Mr. Spock, you're in command.
明白
Acknowledged.
辐射水平，正常
Radiation level, normal.
气压，每平方英寸11磅
Atmospheric pressure, 11 pounds per square inch.
过滤系统失灵了，舰长
Filtration systems are out, sir.
整个通讯系统看来也短路了
The whole communication system looks to be shorted out too.
史考特，去看看相位炮发射过没有 老骨头，你跟我来
Scotty, see if the phaser banks have been fired. Bones, you come with me.
行动吧，各位
Come along, lad.
真是一团糟
What a mess.
没有乱七八糟，没有喝一半的咖啡
No clutter, no half-empty cups of coffee.
不管发生了什么，都是有预警的
Whatever happened didn't happen without a warning.
你觉得是谁干的，舰长？
What do you think did it, sir?
我不知道
I don't know, lad
但是我要作全面的结构检查 以及损伤控制检查
but I want a full structural and control-damage check.
我去看看引擎
And I'm gonna have a look at those engines.
船员没有被劫持，他们是自愿离开的，寇克呼叫进取号
The crew wasn't abducted, they just left. Kirk to Enterprise.
进取号收到，我是史波克
Enterprise, Spock here.
没有幸存者，也没有尸体
No survivors. No bodies either.
有没有可能他们是被传送到某个行星上去了？
Is it possible they were beamed down to one of the two planets?
不太可能，舰长，一颗行星的表面温度足以
Improbable, captain. The surface temperature of the inner planet
使人融化
is that of molten lead.
而另一颗星球的大气对人类来说有毒
The other has an atmosphere poisonous to human life.
我们仍在调查，完毕
We'll continue our search. Kirk out.
舰长，我检查过引擎了
Captain, I checked the engines.
曲速引擎完全失效，形同虚设
The warp drive, that's a hopeless pile of junk.
脉冲引擎受损不是很严重
The impulse engines are not too badly off. We'll be able
- 应该能够派上用场 - 相位炮呢？
- to do something with them. - Phaser banks?
耗尽了，他们肯定是搏斗一番才弃船的
Exhausted. They didn't give up without a battle.
可是他们究竟在哪里？
But where are they?
马特·德克尔这样的人怎么可能弃船呢
I can't imagine a man like Matt Decker abandoning ship
更何况生命维持系统还在运转
while his life-support systems are still operative.
计算机系统还是完好的，我们可以
The computer system is still intact. We can play back
从辅助控制室调取舰长日志的副本
the duplicate captain's log from the Auxiliary Control Room.
马特
Matt.
马特，我是吉姆·寇克
Matt. It's Jim Kirk.
准将？德克尔准将？
Commodore? Commodore Decker?
马特
Matt.
我是寇克，吉姆·寇克啊
Kirk. It's Jim Kirk.
你的星舰怎么了，马特？
What happened to your ship, Matt?
星舰被攻击了…那个…那个东西
A ship attacked... That... That thing.
- 什么东西？是什么东西？ - 是…
- What thing? What was it? - That...
回答我，是什么？发生了什么，马特？
Answer me. What was it? What happened, Matt?
吉姆，给他点时间，他吓坏了
Jim, give him a minute. He's in a state of shock.
准备好听舰长日志了吗，长官
Ready with the duplicate log, sir.
放吧
Go.
舰长日志，星历4202.1，异常强烈的
Captain's log, stardate 4202. 1. Exceptionally heavy
子空间干扰持续影响我们与星际舰队取得联系
subspace interference still prevents our contacting Starfleet
使得我们无法向星际舰队报告 我们所遇到的已毁灭星系
to inform them of the destroyed solar systems we have encountered.
我们正在进入L374星系
We are now entering System L374.
科学官马萨达报告称第四颗行星
Science Officer Masada reports the fourth planet
似乎分解了，我们正前去调查
seems to be breaking up. We are going to investigate.
第四行星，现在只剩下两颗了
The fourth planet. Only two left now.
史考特，把传感器内存条的微型磁带取下来
Scotty, pull the microtapes from the sensor memory banks and beam them
传给史波克，让他做全面分析
to Spock. I want a full analysis,
对这一行星上所发生的事情做以全面报告
a complete report of what happened on that planet.
是，舰长
Aye, sir.
我们试图联系星际舰队
We tried to contact Starfleet.
没有人回应，一个都没有
No one heard. No one.
- 我们无法逃离 - 你的船员呢？
- We couldn't run. - What happened to your crew?
哦，我把他们传下去了，我们快死了
Oh, I had to beam them down. We were dead. No power.
没有能源相位炮派不上用场，我留下了，最后一个人
Our phasers, useless. I stayed behind. Last man.
舰长，最后一个留在星舰上的人
The captain, last man aboard the ship.
这是分内之事，对吧？
That's what you're supposed to do, isn't it?
然后那东西又攻击了一次，传送器就失灵了
And then it hit again and the transporter went out.
他们在下面，而我在这里
There they were down there, and I'm up here.
什么攻击？是什么攻击了你们？
What hit? What attacked you?
人们说世上没有魔鬼，吉姆
They say there's no devil, Jim.
原来真的有
But there is.
就从地狱来！我亲眼所见！
Right out of hell! I saw it!
马特，你的船员呢？
Matt, where's your crew?
在第三颗行星上
On the third planet.
根本就没有第三颗行星
There is no third planet.
你以为我不知道吗？本来有的，现在没了
Don't you think I know that? There was, but not anymore.
他们联系我，求我救他们，整整400人啊
They called me. They begged me for help, 400 of them.
我做不到！我…做不到啊
I couldn't! I... I couldn't.
舰长，沃什博恩做出报告了
Captain, Washburn has our report.
- 去吧 - 我们对星舰结构和损毁控制
- Go. - We made a complete check
做了完整的检查，舰长
on structural and control damage, sir.
从目前的情况看来，什么东西穿过了了偏转器
As far as we can tell, something crashed through the deflectors
毁坏了发动机
and knocked out the generators.
不知为何曲速引擎舱中的反物质失去了活性
Somehow the antimatter in the warp-drive pods has been deactivated.
失去了活性？史考特，会不会是某种普遍的
Deactivated. Scotty, could some kind of general,
能量抑制场造成的？ 会不会高强度子空间干扰
energy-dampening field do that? And would the same type of thing
也是它造成的？
account for the heavy subspace interference?
是，说的有道理
Aye, it all adds up.
可是什么 东西才能造成这么多问题呢？
But what sort of a thing could do all that?
你们看到就明白了，那东西整个就是武器，绝对是
If you'd seen it, you'd know. The whole thing's a weapon, it must be.
- 它长什么样子？ - 嗯，有好几英里长
- What does it look like? - Well, it's miles long,
长着一张大嘴，可以吞下十几艘星舰
with a maw that could swallow a dozen starships.
它毁灭行星，把行星劈成碎石
It destroys planets, chops them into rubble.
究竟是什么，是外星人飞船？它是活的还是…？
What is it, an alien ship? Or is it alive or..?
两者皆是，或者皆不是，我不知道
Both. Or neither. I don't know.
马特，你的日志上说第四颗行星解体了
Matt, your log stated that the fourth planet was breaking up.
- 你们调查过了吗？ - 我们亲眼看见它
- You went in to investigate. - We saw it
盘旋过那行星，生生用一道
hovering over the planet, slicing out chunks of it
射线将其切割成块
with a force beam.
你们有没有扫描过？是哪种射线？
Did you run a scanner check on it? What kind of a beam?
纯粹的反质子，绝对纯粹
Pure antiproton. Absolutely pure.
- 寇克收到 - 我是史波克，舰长
- Kirk here. - Spock here, captain.
由于子空间干扰十分强烈，无法联系到星际舰队
Unable to raise Starfleet Command due to heavy subspace interference.
- 正在尝试其他方法 - 星座号的磁带分析的怎么样了？
- Attempting to remedy. - What about the Constellation's tapes?
攻击她的东西似乎本质上是机器人
She was attacked by what appears to be essentially a robot.
一种体型庞大、能力惊人的自动化武器
An automated weapon of immense size and power.
我们已经了解到它的功能之一是将行星化为碎石
Its apparent function is to smash planets to rubble
并将其消化作为自身的燃料，因此只要还有行星
and then digest the debris for fuel. It is therefore self-sustaining,
它就可以源源不断的维持生命
as long as there are planetary bodies for it to feed on.
一个有意毁灭整个类太阳星系的机器人武器
A robot weapon that purposely destroys entire solar systems.
- 为什么它这样做？ - 不了解，舰长
- Why? - Unknown, captain.
不过，苏鲁先生已经根据已被毁灭的星系
However, Mr. Sulu has computed the path of the machine
计算出了这机器的路径
using the destroyed solar systems as a base course.
反映到我们的星图上，可以看到它来自于
Projecting back on our star charts, we find that it came from outside,
遥远的其他星系
from another galaxy.
那么这东西的预定路线是什么？
And what is the projected course of this thing?
若遵循目前的路径
If it follows its present path,
它会经过我们银河系中
it will go through the most densely populated section
人口最密集的区域
of our galaxy.
谢谢你，待命，史波克先生，完毕
Thank you. Stand by, Mr. Spock. Kirk out.
难以置信，一个机器人
This whole thing's incredible. A robot, a machine like that,
究竟是谁建造了它？
who would build it?
我们不知道，来自其他星系的外星种族吧
We don't know. An alien race apparently from another galaxy.
可是为什么呢？
But why?
老骨头
Bones,
你听说过末日机器吗？
did you ever hear of a doomsday machine?
没有，我是个医生，不是机械师
No. I'm a doctor, not a mechanic.
它是个武器，主要是用来恐吓敌人
It's a weapon, built primarily as a bluff.
这东西就不应该被使用
It's never meant to be used.
它太强大了，能够毁灭战争双方
So strong it could destroy both sides in a war.
就像以前的氢弹一样
Something like the old H-bomb was supposed to be.
它就是这么一种东西
That's what I think this is.
无数年前某些人使用过的末日机器
A doomsday machine that somebody used in a war uncounted years ago.
那些人已经不存在了，可机器还在大开杀戒
They don't exist anymore but the machine is still destroying.
哦，别纸上谈兵了！
Oh, forget about your theories!
那东西正朝我们星系的中心地带直奔而去
That thing is on the way to the heart of our galaxy.
- 你打算怎么做？ - 别着急
- What are you gonna do? - Take it easy.
首先，我们要让你回去
First thing we're gonna do is get you back.
不行，我留在这里，我不会抛弃我的星舰…
Oh, no, I stay here. I'm not leaving my ship...
你的星舰已经不存在了，这只是个尸体而已
There's no ship to leave. It's a dead hulk.
我们会拖走她，我会待在这里做好准备
We'll take her in tow. I'll stay onboard and get her ready.
你跟医生一起回进取号，他会帮助你
You go back to the Enterprise with the doctor and let him help you.
只是我从来没有把指挥权交给别人过
It's just that I never lost a command before.
寇克呼叫进取号
Kirk to Enterprise.
准备好传送室
Have the Transporter Room
立即传送麦考伊医生和德克尔准将回进取号
beam Dr. McCoy and Commodore Decker onboard immediately.
红色警报！红色警报！
Red alert! Red alert!
快走
Come on.
它的速度很快，不过我们目前还可以与之保持距离
It came up on us fast, captain, but we seem able to maintain our distance.
我这边看不到，它长什么样子？
I'm blind here. What's it look like?
看起来非常像德克尔准将所说的行星杀手
It looks very much like Commodore Decker's planet killer.
而且它在追杀我们
And it is pursuing us.
相较之下，我们更灵活，但是它正逼近我们
We are more manoeuvrable, but it is gaining on us.
传感器显示存在某种变频驱动
Sensors indicate some kind of total conversion drive.
没有生命迹象，子空间干扰十分强烈
No evidence of life. Subspace interference level incredibly high.
不管它是什么
Whatever it is
我们都不能让它超过我们，去毁灭下一个类太阳系
we can't let it go beyond us to the next solar system.
我们必须阻止它
We have to stop it.
如果它是机器人，那么我们使其失灵的可能性有多大？
If it's a robot, what are the chances of deactivating it?
可以说没有，舰长
I would say none, captain.
我们动力舱的能量似乎吸引着它
The energy generated by our power nacelles seems to attract it.
我估计近距离攻击它
I doubt we could manoeuvre close enough
可能会遭受强烈反击
without drawing a direct attack upon ourselves.
考虑到这是台自动机器
I also believe the nature of this machine precludes the possibility
从外部控制它的可能性很小
of easy access to its control mechanisms.
- 它接近我们了，史波克先生 - 接近了，舰长
- It's closing on us, Mr. Spock. - Closing, captain.
好了，降低偏转器能量，传送我们回去
All right. Lower your deflector screens long enough to beam us aboard.
明白
Acknowledged.
传送室，准备传送陆上部队回舰
Transporter Room, stand by to beam landing party aboard.
准备完毕，长官
Ready to beam, sir.
苏鲁先生，所有单位，报告损伤
Evasive action, Mr. Sulu. Damage report, all stations.
- 史波克先生，传送室失灵了 - 迅速修复
- Mr. Spock, the transporter's out. - Effect repairs.
- 寇克舰长，请回答 - 寇克收到
- Captain Kirk, come in, please. - Kirk here.
舰长，我们收到攻击了，传送室受到损伤
Captain, we've been attacked. Transporter is damaged.
我们准备采取避让措施
We're taking evasive action.
史波克先生，通讯受损，我们无法克服干扰
Mr. Spock, communication's damaged. We're unable to override interference.
通讯受损，舰长，干扰会…
Damage in communications, captain. Interference will...
史波克，史波克
Spock. Spock.
能听见吗，史波克，史波克？
Come in, Spock. Spock?
- 我们困在这里了，又聋又瞎 - 而且还瘫痪了，没有电力
- We're stuck. Blind and deaf. - And paralyzed. No power.
我们不能就这么坐视进取号被攻击
Well, we just can't stand around while our ship is being attacked.
你必须得想办法弄点动力啊
You've got to get me some manoeuvring power.
只有在太空港才能修复曲速引擎
I can't repair a warp drive without a space dock.
那就脉冲引擎，一半速度或者四分之一的速度都行
Then get me impulse power, half-speed, quarter-speed, anything.
如果我们能让这大家伙动起来，说不定可以做些什么
If we can get this hulk moving, maybe we can do something.
脉冲引擎状态还行，说不定可以用得上
The impulse engines are still in fair shape. I might coax them.
- 那快行动吧 - 走吧，小子
- Then get moving. - Come along, lad.
沃什博恩，你去那边
Washburn, you get in there.
看看能不能修好这个显示器
Let's see what we can do about this viewing screen.
我得搞清楚到底发生了什么
I've got to find out what's happening out there.
没有人员伤亡，史波克先生，怎么样了？
No casualties, Mr. Spock. How are we doing?
我们速度比它快，医生
We have outrun it, doctor.
报告状态
Status report.
脉冲引擎和曲速引擎运转良好
Impulse and warp engines operative.
传送室和通讯设施正在修复
Transporter and communications under repair.
看来机会站在我们这一边的
Random chance seems to have operated in our favour.
简单来说就是，我们运气挺好
In plain, non-Vulcan English, we've been lucky.
我就是这么说的，医生
I believe I said that, doctor.
它改变方向了，正前往下一个类太阳系
It's veering off. Back on course for the next solar system.
是参宿七殖民地，长官
The Rigel colonies, sir.
看来其程序设定了在超过某一半径之后
Evidently programmed to ignore anything as small as a ship
它就会自动忽略星舰这么小的目标
beyond a certain radius.
我们保持适当的距离
We'll maintain a discreet distance
绕回去营救舰长
and circle back to pick up the captain.
你不能就这么放任它前往参宿七
You can't let that thing reach Rigel.
无数无辜的人会死的
Millions of innocent people would die.
我很了解参宿七星的人口，准将
I am aware of the Rigel system's population, commodore,
但我们只有一艘星舰，偏转器保护盾也只勉强可以用
but we are only one ship. Our deflector shields are strained.
子空间发射机形同虚设
Our subspace transmitter is useless.
按照逻辑，我们的首要任务是逃生，并警告星际舰队
Logically, our primary duty is to survive in order to warn Starfleet Command.
我们的首要任务是保护星际联邦的生命安全
Our primary duty is to maintain life and the safety of Federation planets.
你不这么认为吗？
Do you deny that?
苏鲁先生，请你设定回避路线，返回星座号
Mr. Sulu, you will lay in an evasive course back to the Constellation.
- 是，先生 - 牢记这条命令，舵手
- Aye, aye, sir. - Belay that last order, helmsman.
180度转弯，右满舵，准备出击
One hundred and eighty degree turn, hard about. We're going to attack.
执行我刚才的命令，苏鲁先生
You will carry out my last order, Mr. Sulu.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
我正式通知你
I am officially notifying you
根据星际舰队准将条例
that I am exercising my option
我将行使我的权力
under regulations as a Starfleet commodore,
也就是说，我将接任进取号的指挥官
and that I am assuming command of the Enterprise.
你有这么做的权力
You have the right to do so
但是我建议不要这么做
but I would advise against it.
那东西必须被摧毁
That thing must be destroyed.
你曾尝试过一次，准将
You tried to destroy it once before, commodore.
其结果是星舰失事，船员牺牲
The result was a wrecked ship and a dead crew.
那次是我的失误，我们太深入了
I made a mistake then. We were too far away.
这次我打算在近距离平射射程以全部相位炮攻击它
This time I'm going to hit it with full phasers at point-blank range.
传感器显示这东西的外壳是固体中子态
Sensors show the object's hull is solid neutronium.
单单一艘星舰无法与之匹敌
A single ship cannot combat it.
史波克先生，就这样吧
Mr. Spock, that will be all.
你被解除指挥官职务了
You have been relieved of command.
不要逼我也解除你的大副职务
Don't force me to relieve you of duty as well.
你不能让他这样做，史波克
You can't let him do this, Spock.
医生，你越界了
Doctor, you are out of line.
你也是…先生
So are you... sir.
史波克？
Well, Spock?
不幸的是，根据星际舰队章程B部分的104条规定 我别无选择
Unfortunately, Starfleet Order 104, Section B, leaves me no alternative.
1A一段中明确说明…
Paragraph 1 A clearly states...
别管什么条例了！你明知道他是错的
To blazes with regulations! You can't let him take command
怎么能让他接手指挥权
when you know he's wrong.
如果你能证明德克尔准将生理
If you can certify Commodore Decker
或心理上不适合担任指挥官一职
medically or psychologically unfit for command,
我便可以根据C部分的规定解除他的职务
I can relieve him under Section C.
我现在就可以证明
I'll certify that right now.
根据规定，你还得出示医疗记录以证明结果的真实性
You will also be asked to produce your medical records to prove it.
你知道我现在没时间对他做检查
Now, you know I haven't had time to run an examination on him.
那么你的证明就不具有法律效力
Then your statement would not be considered valid.
你可以退下了，医生
You may leave the Bridge, doctor.
那舰长呢？我不能丢下…
What about the captain? We can't leave...
医生，你可以退下了
Doctor, you may leave the Bridge.
史波克！想想办法啊！
Spock! Do something!
史波克先生清楚自己的职责所在，医生
Mr. Spock knows his duty under regulations, doctor.
那你呢？
Do you?
右满舵，舵手，路径：32度，标记10
Hard about, helmsman. Course: 32 degrees, mark 10.
偏转器全功率开启，准备好主相位炮
Deflectors at full power. Ready on main phaser banks.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
- 我是寇克 - 舰长
- Kirk here. - Captain,
脉冲引擎的控制回路被融化成固体了
the impulse engines' control circuits are fused solid.
曲速引擎控制回路呢？
What about the warp drive control circuits?
对，我们可以交叉连接控制回路
Aye, we can cross-connect the controls,
但是一个人无法操作星舰啊
but the ship'll be almost impossible for one man to handle.
操心你自己的工作吧，史考特 我操心我的就好了，快工作
Worry about your miracles, Scotty, I'll worry about mine. Get to work.
是，舰长
Aye, sir.
沃什博恩，试试2G6回路
Washburn, try the 2G6 circuit.
快速接近中
Closing fast.
偏转器全功率开启中，不能再多了
Deflector shields at full power. They can't take much more of this.
舵手，保持航向 全部相位炮，待命
Helmsman, hold your course. Stand by, all phaser banks.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
偏转器还挺得住，不过在变弱 准将，我们必须撤退
Deflectors holding, but weakening. We must retreat, commodore.
- 能量流失… - 我才是指挥官，史波克先生
- The energy drain... - I'm in command here, Mr. Spock.
维持航向不变，舵手，接近它
Maintain your course, helmsman. Get us in closer.
- 准备好试一试了吗？ - 马上就好，舰长
- Ready to give it a try? - Just one minute, sir.
史考特，你那边怎么样？
Scotty, how are you doing?
控制回路已全部连接，舰长
Controls are all hooked up, sir
我们应该留一些动力供你一会儿使用
We should have some power for you soon.
现在试试，舰长
Try it now, captain.
是，我想…
Yes, I think...
这是怎么回事？
What the devil's going on?
开火！
Fire!
直接攻击
Direct hit.
反弹回来了
They just bounced off.
准将，我强烈建议马上撤离
Commodore, I urgently recommend immediate withdrawal.
我知道了，保持航向，开火！
Recommendation noted. Maintain course. Fire!
寇克呼叫进取号，请回答
Kirk to Enterprise. Come in.
进取号，请回答 史波克先生，请回答
Enterprise, come in. Mr. Spock, come in.
寇克呼叫进… 史考特，我要的动力呢？
Kirk to Enterpri... Scotty, where's that power?
马上就好，舰长，按照目前的状态
Coming, sir. If I push these impulse engines
如果脉冲引擎使用过度的话，会爆炸的
too hard in the condition they're in, they'll blow apart.
沃什博恩去轮机室，帮帮史考特
Washburn, go down to Engineering, assist Mr. Scott.
是，舰长
Aye, sir.
史考特，将脉冲引擎开到最大
Scotty, push it right to the edge.
这艘星舰必须动起来
This ship has got to manoeuvre.
是，舰长
Aye, sir.
长官，偏转器防护盾失效了
Sir, deflector shields are gone.
长官，7号甲班报告主引擎动力衰竭
Sir, Deck 7 reports power failure in main energisers.
启动应急方案
Implementing emergency procedures.
3号、4号甲板报告称人员伤亡严重
Severe casualties reported on Decks 3 and 4.
损伤控制组封住了船体开口
Damage-control party sealing off inner-hull rupture.
它停火了，我们被一股牵引光束包围了
It has ceased fire. We're being held in a tractor beam.
我们要被拖进去了，准将，我们必须撤退
We're being pulled inside, commodore. You must veer off.
保持相位炮攻击不变，舵手
Maintain phaser fire, helmsman.
我们已经失去曲速引擎了
We have lost warp power.
如果不在60秒内摆脱牵引光束
If we don't break the tractor beam
就逃脱不了了
within 60 seconds, we never will.
你难道不明白吗？我们必须得摧毁它
But don't you understand? We've got to destroy it!
这不合逻辑，长官
That, sir, is illogical.
这种企图自杀的行为可以证明你
It is suicide. Attempted suicide would be proof
心理上不适合担任指挥官
that you are psychologically unfit for command.
如果你不撤退
If you don't veer off,
我将据此解除你的职务
I shall relieve you on that basis.
- 撤退！ - 应急脉冲动力
- Veer off! - Emergency impulse power.
- 我们甩不掉它的 - 需要更多动力
- We can't break loose. - We need more power.
没有其他动力了！我们被拖进去了
We haven't got it! We're being pulled inside.
史考特，我要的动力呢
Scotty, give me that power.
马上就来，舰长
You've got it, captain.
刚好可以让星舰动起来 再多的我也无能为力了
Just enough to move us. I can't do better.
这样就行了
That'll do.
全速前进，史考特先生
Full ahead, Mr. Scott.
就是这样，史考特先生
That's it, Mr. Scott.
保持动力
Keep that power coming.
- 全力后退 - 是，长官
- Full power astern. - Aye, sir.
我们还是动不了
We still can't move.
保持动力，史考特
Keep pouring it on, Scotty.
舰长，我还是没搞清明白我们要干嘛
Captain, I still don't know what we're doing.
我们可以动，但是进取号动不了
We're moving. The Enterprise isn't.
说不定那东西能看到我们
Maybe that thing will see us
然后放进取号走
and let the Enterprise go.
要是有相位炮就好了
If I only had some phasers.
相位炮？我们有相位炮，有一组刚刚充好电
Phasers? You've got them. I have one bank recharged.
史考特，你刚刚挣到了这周的工资，待命吧
Scotty, you've just earned your pay for the week. Stand by.
相位炮
Fire phasers.
我们摆脱它了，准将
We're loose, commodore.
好家伙，吉姆，悄悄告诉你，我们要宰了那东西
Good boy, Jim. Between the two of us, we'll kill that thing.
史考特先生，成了，太好了！
Mr. Scott, it worked. Great!
确实太好了，史考特，我们快撤
I think it's great. Scotty, get us out of here.
它正快速接近星座号
It's closing fast on the Constellation.
待命，长官
Standing by, sir.
准将，我建议…
Commodore, I suggest...
寇克分散了它的注意力，救了我们，现在该我们了
Kirk pulled us out of there by distracting it. Now it's our turn.
相位炮
Fire phasers.
开火！右满舵，拉开距离
Did it! Hard about. Get me some distance.
我们得离开，准将
We're moving away, commodore.
这东西似乎有设定好的防守范围
This machine seems to have a programmed defensive sphere.
所有进入此范围的能量源都会受到攻击
Any energy source entering that field is subject to attack.
史波克先生，报告状态
Mr. Spock, status report.
未来一个太阳日内，曲速引擎和偏转器都将失效
Warp drive and deflectors will be out for a solar day.
传送及通讯设备仍在维修中
Repairs proceeding on transporter and communications.
- 它又接近我们了，长官 - 保持速度及间距
- It's closing with us again, sir. - Maintain speed and distance.
它在吞噬已毁灭行星的残骸，给自己增加燃料
It's sucking in space rubble from those destroyed planets, refuelling itself.
按照目前的速度，燃料耗尽之前我们有7个小时
We can maintain this speed for seven hours before we exhaust our fuel,
但是它却可以无限补充燃料
but it can refuel itself indefinitely.
那我们就得现在和它决斗，而不是等它变得更强大
Then we'll have to fight it now, before it gets any stronger.
不合逻辑，我们无法摧毁它
Illogical. We cannot destroy it,
因此，我们无法拯救参宿七
therefore, we cannot save Rigel.
我们必须把舰长及其他人从星座号上传回来
We must transport the captain and the others from the Constellation,
然后逃离这东西的子空间干扰范围
and escape this thing's subspace interference
以便警告星际舰队指挥官
in order to warn Starfleet Command.
史波克先生，我们暂时摆脱了信号干扰
Mr. Spock, we've pierced the interference locally.
能联系上星际舰队吗？
Can you raise Starfleet?
不行，但是星舰之间的通讯可以
No, sir, but I've got ship-to-ship communications back.
呼叫寇克舰长
Picking up Captain Kirk.
开启音频，中尉
On audio, lieutenant.
进取号，进取号，收到请回答
Enterprise. Enterprise, come in.
史波克先生，我仍然是指挥官，我代表进取号发言
Mr. Spock, I am still in command and I will speak for this ship.
进取号呼叫寇克
Enterprise to Kirk.
我是德克尔准将
Commodore Decker speaking.
马特？怎么回事？让我跟史波克说话
Matt? What's going on? Give me Mr. Spock.
我现在担任指挥，吉姆
I'm in command here, Jim.
史波克呢？
What happened to Spock?
他很好，根据规定，目前由我来担任指挥官
Nothing. I assumed command according to regulations.
由于你的大副不愿对敌方采取强制措施…
Since your first officer was reluctant to take aggressive action against the...
这么说来你就是那个差点毁了我星舰的疯子？
So you're the lunatic who's responsible for almost destroying my ship?
你在与高级军官对话，寇克
You are speaking to a senior officer, Kirk.
让我跟史波克通话
Give me Spock.
我告诉你
I told you,
根据手册中的规章制度，我是这里的指挥官，舰长
I am in command here, according to every rule in the book, captain.
如果你有话要说，就对我说吧
If you have anything to say at all, you will say it to me.
我想对你说的只有一件事：准将
There's only one thing I wanna say to you, commodore:
带我的星舰离开那鬼地方！
Get my ship out of there!
史波克先生？报告星舰状态
Mr. Spock? Ship status.
准将？
Commodore?
说吧
Down here.
曲速引擎失效
Warp drive out.
偏转器防护盾失效，传送室正在维修
Deflector shields down. Transporter under repair.
我们现在使用的是应急脉冲动力
We are on emergency impulse power.
维修曲速引擎需要多久？
How long to repair warp drive?
至少一个太阳日
At least one solar day.
按照目前的消耗
At our present rate of consumption,
我们的脉冲引擎撑不到那个时候
we'll exhaust our impulse power long before then.
它快追上来了，长官
It's gaining on us, sir.
躲开它，苏鲁先生
Take evasive action, Mr. Sulu.
告诉你，我是这里的指挥官
I told you, I am in command here
我来 发出命令，舰长
and I will give the orders, captain.
我们要掉头去攻击它
We are going to turn and attack.
休想带着我的星舰去送死
Not with my ship, you don't.
史波克，立即解除德克尔准将的职位
Spock, relieve Commodore Decker immediately.
这是一条直接命令
That's a direct order.
你不能解除我的职务
You can't relieve me
你自己清楚，根据规定…
and you know it. According to regulations...
去他的规定
Blast regulations.
史波克先生 我以进取号舰长的身份
Mr. Spock, I order you to assume command
命令你接任指挥官
on my personal authority as captain of the Enterprise.
德克尔准将，你被解除职务了
Commodore Decker, you are relieved of command.
你有什么权力可以解除我的职务
I don't recognise your authority to relieve me.
你可以向星际舰队提出正式抗议
You may file a formal protest with Starfleet Command,
前提是我们能够活着抵达星际基地
assuming we survive to reach a starbase.
但目前你确实是被解职了
But you are relieved.
准将，我不希望拘捕你
Commodore, I do not wish to place you under arrest.
你不敢
You wouldn't dare.
你只是虚张声势
You're bluffing.
瓦肯人从不虚张声势
Vulcans never bluff.
是
No.
没错，我想也是
No, I don't suppose that they do.
很好，史波克先生，舰桥是你的了
Very well, Mr. Spock. The Bridge is yours.
舰长，我拿到指挥权了
Captain, I have assumed command.
很好，史波克先生…
Good. Now, Mr. Spock...
稍等，舰长，准将，我想你还有一个
One moment, sir. Commodore, I believe you were
健康检查要做
scheduled for medical examination.
- 蒙哥马利先生 - 长官？
- Mr. Montgomery. - Sir?
护送准将去医务室
Accompany the commodore to Sickbay.
是，长官，准将，请吧
Aye, sir. Commodore.
苏鲁先生，改变航向：7-0，标记2-1
Mr. Sulu. Change course: 7-0, mark 2-1.
标记21，长官
Mark 21, sir.
舰长，我们正采取迂回路线返回营救你们
Captain, we are taking an evasive course back to you.
我们会尽量处于那东西前方，直到将你们传送回来
We will try to stay ahead of the object until we can transport you aboard.
好，一定要确保不被它追上
Fine. Just make sure you stay ahead of it.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
怎么了，史考特？
Yeah, Scotty?
我已经连上了星舰的通讯设备
I've hooked in ship's communication.
但是引擎最大也只能提供
The best I can give you on impulse
三分之一的动力
is one-third power.
防护罩可以用了 但是坚持不了多久
The shields are up, but they won't last long.
保持住，史考特，保持住
Keep it going, Scotty. Keep her going.
- 史波克先生 - 是，舰长
- Mr. Spock. - Yes, sir.
我设置了阻截航向，将与你在
I'm plotting an intercept course. We'll rendezvous with you
1413.7时会合
at 1413.7 hours.
史波克先生，有人打开了航天飞机舱门
Mr. Spock, someone's opening the shuttlecraft bay doors.
- 拦截他，苏鲁先生 - 来不及了，长官
- Shut them, Mr. Sulu. - It's too late, sir.
寇克呼叫进取号，你们为什么发射航天飞机？
Kirk to Enterprise. Why are you launching a shuttlecraft?
我并未授权，此人是擅自行动
Whoever it is, captain, has no authorisation.
中尉，呼叫航天飞机
Lieutenant, raise the shuttlecraft.
进取号呼叫航天飞机，请回答
Enterprise to shuttlecraft. Come in, shuttlecraft.
请回答，航天飞机
Come in, shuttlecraft.
航天飞机呼叫进取号，我是德克尔
Shuttlecraft to Enterprise. Decker here.
准将，请你立即回舰
Commodore, I must insist that you return to the ship.
你自己也说过，史波克
You said it yourself, Spock.
我们绝不可能炸穿那机器的船身
There is no way to blast through the hull of that machine,
所以我要直捣它的喉咙
so I'm gonna take this thing right down its throat.
我是寇克，马特，你这是送死啊
This is Kirk. Matt, you'll be killed.
自从…自从我害死了我的全体船员之后
I've been prepared for death ever since I...
我就做好了赴死的准备
Ever since I killed my crew.
没有人要求你因一次判断错误而去送死
No one expects you to die for an error in judgement.
指挥官应对船员的生命负责
A commander is responsible for the lives of his crew.
也要对船员们的死亡负责
And for their deaths.
我也应该与我的船员同生共死
Well, I should have died with mine.
你不可能成功的，准将
You cannot succeed, commodore.
唯一合理的选择是立即返回进取号
Your only logical alternative is to return to the ship.
马特，马特，听我说
Matt. Matt, listen to me.
你不能就这样白白送命
You can't throw your life away like this.
马特，你是一名星舰指挥官
Matt, you're a starship commander.
你有自己的价值所在
That makes you a valuable commodity.
我们需要你，需要你的经验，你的判断力，马特！
We need you, your experience, your judgement. Matt!
我们和你在一起时更强大
We're stronger with you than without you.
他死了
He's gone.
星座号，请回答
Constellation, come in, please.
寇克舰长，请回答
Captain Kirk, come in, please.
- 我是寇克 - 舰长
- Kirk here. - Sir,
请接受我对您朋友之死的哀悼
may I offer my condolences on the death of your friend?
这真是令人遗憾
It is most regrettable.
令人遗憾的是他就这样白白牺牲了
It's regrettable that he died for nothing.
史波克先生，传感器显示那机器的能量发射
Mr. Spock, sensors indicate a minute drop
出现了一分钟下降
in the machine's power emanations.
会不会航天飞机的爆炸对它造成了一些伤害？
Do you think the shuttlecraft explosion might have done some damage?
你觉得呢，史波克？这有可能吗？
What about that, Spock? Is it possible?
确实存在能量下降，但是可以忽略不计
The drop in power is definite, captain, but negligible.
那东西还在追我们
The object is still pursuing us,
因此我们的能量消耗十分快
thereby causing us to drain our power reserve at a much greater rate.
史波克先生，传送室可以使用了
Mr. Spock, the transporter is now operational.
传送室可以用了，舰长，要我们传送你回舰吗？
Transporter operational, captain. Shall we beam you aboard?
否定，史考特先生和我继续留在这里
Negative. Mr. Scott and I will stay here,
但是请传送损伤控制组回舰
but beam the damage-control party aboard.
舰长，留在星座号上没有任何作用
Captain, there is little to be gained by staying aboard the Constellation.
除非…
Except possibly...
有可能摧毁那东西
...the destruction of that thing out there.
执行命令，史波克先生
Carry out your orders, Mr. Spock.
明白
Acknowledged.
传送室，将损伤控制组传送回舰
Transporter Room, beam damage-control party aboard.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
史波克，听我说
Spock, listen.
也许马特·德克尔并不是白白牺牲的
Maybe Matt Decker didn't die for nothing.
他的想法是对的，但是没有足够的能量
He had the right idea, but not enough power to do it.
若一艘星舰脉冲引擎超负荷的话
Am I correct in assuming that a fusion explosion of 97 megatons will result
其爆炸是不是会造成9700万吨能量？
if a starship impulse engine is overloaded?
不对，舰长，是9783.5万吨
No, sir, 97.835 megatons.
97.835
足够摧毁那东西了吧？
Will it be powerful enough to destroy that thing out there?
不行，舰长，其船体是纯中子态的
Negative, captain. Its hull is pure neutronium.
目前没有已知的办法能够摧毁它
There is no known way of blasting through it.
我不是要穿过它，而是从内部摧毁它
Not through it, Spock, from inside it.
你觉得足够吗？
Will it be enough?
数据不足，我会获取更多传感器信息
Insufficient data. I shall try to take further sensor readings.
越快越好
Do the best you can, and make it fast.
- 寇克呼叫史考特 - 收到，舰长
- Kirk to Scott. - Here, sir.
损伤控制组刚刚被传送回进取号
The damage-control party just beamed back to the Enterprise.
很好，史考特，你能把脉冲引擎设置到超负荷吗？
Good. Scotty, can you set the ship's impulse engines to overload?
可以，按照这引擎目前的状态，很难不爆炸啊
Aye. The shape the thing's in, it's hard to keep it from blowing.
我需要你给上面安装30秒延迟爆破装置
I want you to rig a 30-second-delay detonation device.
让它能够由这里控制
And rig it so that it can be blown from up here.
是，舰长
Aye, sir.
- 设定好，然后迅速离开 - 马上就办
- Set it and get up here fast. - Right away.
舰长
Captain.
这物体的中子态外壳使得传感器
The object's neutronium hull makes sensor readings
无法探测内部结构
of the inner mechanism impossible.
- 史波克，你不知道？ - 正确
- Spock, you don't know? - Correct.
舰长，你离那行星杀手越来越近了，十分危险
Captain, you're getting dangerously close to the planet killer.
我打算再近一点
I intend to get a lot closer.
我要让她直捣那东西的喉咙
I'm gonna ram her right down that thing's throat.
吉姆，你会死的，就像德克尔一样
Jim, you'll be killed, just like Decker.
不，不，我没有打算去送死，史波克先生
No. No, I don't intend to die, Mr. Spock.
我们安装了延迟爆破装置
We've rigged a delayed-detonation device.
在星座号脉冲引擎爆炸之前
You'll have 30 seconds to beam me aboard the Enterprise
你们有30秒时间传送我回进取号
before the Constellation's impulse engines blow.
你活下来的几率并不乐观
Your chances of survival are not promising.
我们都不知道爆炸所产生的能量是否足够摧毁它
We don't even know if the explosion will be powerful enough.
- 这是预期风险，史波克先生 - 还有一点，舰长
- A calculated risk, Mr. Spock. - There's another factor, captain.
传送室并非处于完全工作的状态
The transporter is not working at 100 percent efficiency.
30秒时间十分紧张
Thirty seconds is very slim timing.
我必须冒这个险，完毕
A chance I'll have to take. Kirk out.
你可不能把自己的性命押在一台
A cranky transporter's a mighty finicky piece of machinery
时常出问题的机器上啊，舰长
to be gambling your life on, sir.
延迟装置怎么样了？
What about the detonator?
我把它和脉冲控制系统连在一起了
I've linked it in with the impulse control system.
现在可以用了
It's armed now.
按这个按钮，30秒后，砰！
Press this one, 30 seconds later, poof!
一旦启动，就无法再停止
Once it's activated, there's no way to stop it.
明白
Understood.
史波克先生，准备传史考特回舰
Mr. Spock, prepare to beam Scotty onboard.
传送室，待命
Transporter, stand by.
- 祝你好运，舰长 - 谢谢你
- Good luck, captain. - Thank you.
这东西怎么回事？
What's the matter with that thing?
某个地方有能量泄露，长官，差点没能传回你
It's a power drain somewhere, sir. I almost lost you.
这样可不行，这可是主要连接系统，我来看看
It'll never work like this. It's the main junction circuitry. I'll get it.
舰桥，传送室发生故障
Bridge. Transporter malfunction.
传送室失效，舰长，你得等等
The transporter is out, captain. You'll have to stand by.
不行，能量水平下降太快了
I can't. Power level's dropping too fast.
- 他得快点 - 明白
- He'd better hurry. - Acknowledged.
史考特先生，时间就是生命啊
Mr. Scott, speed is of the essence.
他离那行星杀手还有2,000英里，还在快速接近
He's 2,000 miles from the planet killer and closing fast.
舰桥，传送室可以使用
Bridge. Transporter operational
但是应急备用设备坚持不了多久
but this jury-rigging won't last for long.
他必须马上离开
He's got to come off now.
- 我待命 - 1,500英里，仍在接近
- I'll stand by here. - Fifteen hundred miles and closing.
舰长，传送室勉强可以使用
Captain, transporter operational, but just barely.
等我信号，准备传送我回去
Prepare to beam me aboard on my signal.
1,000英里，仍在接近
One thousand miles and closing.
- 传送室，待命 - 待命，长官
- Transporter, stand by. - Standing by, sir.
500英里，仍在接近
Five hundred miles and closing.
- 传我回舰 - 供给能量
- Beam me aboard. - Energise.
供给能量
Energising.
舰桥，又短路了
Bridge, it shorted out again.
各位，传我回舰
Gentlemen, beam me aboard.
不行，舰长，传送室又失灵了
We can't, captain. Transporter is out again.
史考特先生，距离爆破还有20秒
Mr. Scott, 20 seconds to detonation.
史考特先生
Mr. Scott.
Mr. Scott,
试试反相位
try inverse phasing.
16，15，14，13…
Sixteen, 15, 14, 13...
先生们，我强烈建议传送我回去
Gentlemen, I suggest you beam me aboard.
10，9，8
Ten, nine, eight,
- 史考特先生 - 7，6
- Mr. Scott. - Seven, six,
现在试试，凯尔先生
Try her now, Mr. Kyle.
5，4…
Five, four...
舰桥！他回来了！
Bridge! We got him through!
能量输出，零，辐射水平，正常
Energy output, zero. Radiation level, normal.
欢迎回来，舰长
Welcome aboard, captain.
传感器显示所有能量源全部失效
Sensors show all energy sources deactivated.
它的确死了
It's quite dead.
苏鲁先生，慢慢接近它
Mr. Sulu, ease us back to minimum headway.
节约能源，帕莫尔中尉
Conserve power as much as possible. Lieutenant Palmer
告诉史考特先生，让他加快修复曲速引擎
tell Mr. Scott to expedite repairs on the warp drive.
可怜的马特
Poor Matt,
为了救别人，献出了自己的生命
he gave his life in an attempt to save others.
- 他死得其所 - 的确，舰长
- Not the worst way to go. - Indeed, captain.
我想你的舰长日志中会写德克尔是殉职而死的
I presume your log will show that Decker died in the line of duty.
没错，史波克先生
Indeed it shall, Mr. Spock.
真是讽刺，对吧？20世纪时
Ironic, isn't it? Way back in the 20th century,
氢弹是终极武器，是末日机器
the H-bomb was the ultimate weapon, their doomsday machine.
我们用类似的武器摧毁了另一个末日机器
And we used something like it to destroy another doomsday machine.
这也许是有史以来第一次
Probably the first time such a weapon has ever been used
把这种武器用作建设性目的
for constructive purposes.
这么做很合适，舰长 不过，我不禁想知道
Appropriate, captain. However, I can't help wondering
还有没有类似的武器
if there are any more of those weapons
在宇宙中漫游
wandering around the universe.
我可不希望还有，我觉得一个就够了
Well, I certainly hope not. I found one quite sufficient.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/